Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals M-W, Series II
  - Pearson, Roy M.
    - "The Purpose of preaching." RELIGION IN LIFE 32 (Spring 1963): 267–278. (Box 78)
    - "The fine art of failing in business." PERSONNEL JOURNAL (March 1968): 198–200. (Box 78)
    - Dons Who Bawl. Sermon preached by President Pearson at Andover Newton's opening Chapel service, September 17, 1969. (Box 78)
    - "IS IT I?": A COMMUNION MANIFESTO. [Publication unclear.] (1952–1953?): 57–60., no date (Box 78)
    - BATTLE CALL FOR THE PARISH. (unpublished typewritten manuscript), no date (Box 78)
    - Scyllia and Charybdis. (Unpublished, uncorrected typewritten manuscript for Hillview.), no date (Box 78)
    - THE RELEVANCE OF THE CHURCH TO THE WORLD (unpublished typewritten manuscript)., no date (Box 78)
    - My Name is Simon. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1949. (Box 78)
    - A Faith for These Times. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - Christmas According to Joseph. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - How Important is Sunday?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - Is the Bible True?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - The Need to Decide. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - Unanswered Prayer. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - Watch Our For Your Premises!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - What Are We?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1950. (Box 78)
    - A Christian Approach to Being Drafted. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - All Or Nothing. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - Casting Out Satan. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - If You Were Invisible—. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - Living the Christian Life Today. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - On Feeling Inadequate. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - On Getting a Start in the Christian Life. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - Peace of Mind. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - The Christian Case for Premarital Chastity. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - The Deep Roots of Praise. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - We Don't Want Conscription!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - What About an Ambassador to the Vatican?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - What Does It Mean to Be Humble?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - What Happens When We Die?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - What Is Congregationalism?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - What Kind of Cell Is Your Home?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - Why Are We Protestants?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - Why Didn't You Stay Home?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1951. (Box 78)
    - Being Awfully Good. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Being Willing to Be Wasted. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Don't Be Pushed Around!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Drinking. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Even the Night Shall Be Light About Me. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - For a King: Peculiar Honors. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Get Out of the Church!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Go to Hell!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - I Know He Rose: I Saw Him!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - I'd Rather Be a Pagan. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - It Could Happen Here. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Keeping Your Sanity. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Thank God For Death!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - This Holds a Home Together. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952. (Box 78)
    - Christians in Social Action. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Forty Days in the Wilderness. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - If You Were God. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Love Yourself. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Supposing Him to Be the Gardener. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - The Problem of Being Amphibious. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - When the Best Is Too Bad for the Good. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - When We Worry. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Whewn the World Doesn't Want You. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Why Be a Christian?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Why Not Buddha?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Why the World Is Imperfect. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1953. (Box 78)
    - Dig the Wells Again!: A Sermon on the Contemporary Significance of the Trinity. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - Having Faith In Our Faith. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - On the Anvil of the Desert: A Study of the Lord's Prayer. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - The Day of the Earthquake. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - These Are the Happy. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - What Is a Protestant?. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - When the Roads Diverge. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1954. (Box 78)
    - Pray With Power!. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952–1953. (Box 78)
    - What Good Is Communion? and The Bread and the Cup: Two Communion Meditations. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, 1952–1953. (Box 78)
    - The Fretful Stir Unprofitable. Lexington, MA: Hancock Church Sermons, [no date]. (Box 78)
    - Bibliography of Roy M. Pearson., no date (Box 78)
  - Peck, George W.
    - The Ideal Family and the Familial Ideal. Sermon for Mother's Day—May 14, 1967. (Box 79)
    - Response to Dean John B. Coburn, 'A Perspective on Preparing Men for the Ministry. " Presented at American Baptist Convention, Trinity Church, Boston, May 29, 1968. (Box 79)
    - "A plea for intolerance." Sermon for the Chicago Sunday Evening Club, February 27, 1972. (Box 79)
    - "Review of Christ the Hope of the Future by Warren F. Groff." Foundations 15/4 (October–December 1972): 373–375. (Box 79)
    - "A Plea for Intolerance." The Christian Ministry 4.6 (1973). (Box 79)
    - Reluctant Revolutionaries: Scripture Lesson: Romans 13:1–7. Unpublished manuscript, 1976. (Box 79)
    - Artisans of Peace. Sermon delivered at the Chicago Sunday Evening Club, 70th Season, 1977. (Box 79)
    - "On Speaking Correctly of God." New Conversations Theological Currents: 3.3 (1978/9): 23-26. Draft included., 1978-1979 (Box 79)
    - "Blended together in service: First Baptist and Andover Newton." In To the glory of God on entering the third century: the 200th anniversary of the First Baptist Church In Newton, 1780-1980, 20-22. (Published by the First Baptist Church of Newton Centre, MA 1981.) (Box 79)
    - "Our hope for the years to come." In The one hundred and seventy-fifth anniversary of the Second Baptist Church, Suffield, Connecticut 1805-1980. (Box 79)
    - "Reconceiving the ministry of the laity: a personal testimony." The 99 Percenter New Series 5 (September 1982): 1–3. (Box 79)
    - "World Baptists and the ministry of the laity." Audenshaw Documents, AD 103. Laity Exchange 15 (June 1982). (Box 79)
    - "The Call to Ministry: Its Meaning and Scope." Ministry Development Journal 1.1 (1983). 6-12. (Box 79)
    - "Partnership in mission: beyond the patterns of dependency." In Change and challenge: maintaining the mandate in the Christian world mission, ed. Robert E. Fulop, 56–67. [Valley Forge: ABC/USA,1983]. (Box 79)
    - "Christ's whole body in ministry: recovering a central Biblical image." Laity Exchange 20 (Spring 1984): 1–9. (Box 79)
    - "World mission in our time." (Unpublished address at BWA Council Forum 1984 on Partnership in Mission, July 29, 1984.) [Also in The Australian Baptist, Oct. 17, 1984, 7–8, 12.] (Box 79)
    - "Go tell it to the city." (Unpublished address at the European Baptist Federation Congress in Hamburg, August 1984. This is the complete manuscript GWP intended to present; the actual address that was delivered is in the EBF-Congress documentation.) (Box 79)
    - Draft of "Review of 'Religion in the Secular City: Toward a Post-Modern Theology.'" 1984. (Box 79)
    - "Understanding our call as Baptists: the work of the Commission on the ministry of the laity." (Unpublished address at BWA Congress, Los Angeles, July 1985.) (Box 79)
    - "Of memory and mission." (Unpublished sermon delivered at the public celebration of the three hundredth anniversary of King's Chapel, November 23, 1986.) (Box 79)
    - "Three American Baptist Leaders Encourage Us to Reach Out and … Grow! Grow! Grow! Grow!" The Five Stones 4/2 (Spring 1986): 10. (Box 79)
    - The foundations of mission: a Bible study. Alive in Mission Series. [Valley Forge: ABC/USA, 1986.] (Box 79)
    - The people of the mission: a Bible study. Alive in Mission Series. [Valley Forge: ABC/USA, 1986.] (Box 79)
    - "Jesus Christ the Lord of history in the context of religious pluralism." [Unpublished address delivered at the celebration of the 150th anniversary of the coming of Christianity to N.E. India, February 6, 1986.] (Box 79)
    - "The Heritage of the Haystack." Whole Earth Newsletter 9 (Fall 1981): 5–6. (Box 79)
    - "The dialogue, the mandate, and our hermeneutical perspective: observations of a former missionary." Foundations 25 (March 1982): 31–44. (Box 79)
    - *"Contemporary ministry and the frontiers of meaning." Andover Newton Quarterly 7 (November 1966): 46–65. (Box 79)
    - Harold A. Malmberg, George Peck, and Edwin F. Raylor. This covenant people Valley Forge, PA: Judson Press, 1970. (Box 79)
    - Harold A. Malmberg, George Peck, and Edwin F. Raylor. The covenant people, Teacher's edition. Valley Forge: Judson Press, 1970. (Box 79)
    - "Evangelism rightly so-called: in search of a heritage." New England Journal of Ministry 2 (Spring 1982): 46–53. (Box 79)
    - "A theological environment for effective evangelism." (Lectures presented in Clearwater, Florida, to American Baptist Evangelism Team, January 9–14, 1983.) (Box 79)
    - (1984). "Whither religion in post-modern times?". Boston Sunday Globe. 11 March. (Box 79)
    - "Go tell it to the city." In EBF-Congress 1984 Documentation, 41–49. [Hamburg, Germany, 1984]. (Box 79)
    - " Review of 'Baptist Missions in Nagaland: A Study in Historical and Ecumenical Perspective.'" International Bulletin of Missionary Research 10.1 (1986): 32. (Box 79)
    - "Review of 'Errand to the World: Ameican Protestant Thought and Foreign Missions.'" The Christian Century 104.34 (1987): 1044-1045. (Box 79)
    - Proclamation 3: Pentecost 3, Series A. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1987. (Box 79)
    - (1987). "In Choosing a Seminary, 'It Does Make a Difference'". Today's Ministry. (Volume IV, Issue 2). p.2 (Box 79)
  - Peck, Jane Cary
    - "Reflections on Church and Politics from Costa Rica." [Unpublished manuscript] (August 1981). (Box 65)
    - SELF AND FAMILY. Philidelphia: Westminister Press, 1984. (Box 65)
    - "The United Methodist Agenda: Teaching for Ecumenism." Quarterly Review 11/3 (1991): 71–86. (Box 65)
  - Peery, Russell
    - The Dance of the Old Man. Crossville, Tennessee: A to Z Printing, 2004. (Box 65)
  - Phelps, Austin
    - The Theory of Preaching: An Oration Before the Porter Rhetorical Society of the Theological Seminary at Andover. Andover: W.F. Draper, 1857. (Box 80)
    - The Still Hour; or, Communion with God. Boston: D. Lothrop & Co., 1859. (Box 80)
    - Phelps, Austin, Edwards A. Park, and Daniel L. Furber. Hymns and Choirs: or, the Matter and the Manner of the Service of Song in the House of the Lord. Andover: W.F. Draper, 1860 (Box 80)
    - A Sermon Delivered at the Annual Election, Wednesday, January 2, 1861. Boston: William White, 1861. (Box 80)
    - The Work of the Holy Spirit; or The New Birth. Boston: D. Lothrop and Company, 1881. (Box 80)
    - The Theory of Preaching: Lectures on Homiletics. London: Dickinson, 1882. (Box 80)
    - English Style in Public Discourse With Special Reference to the Usages of the Pulpit. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1883. (Box 80)
  - Pierce, Richard D.
    - The Southworth Lecture, The Cambridge Synod and Platform—1646–1648, Andover Newton Theological School, 10 December 1947. (Box 65)
  - Porter, Ebenezer
    - The Rhetorical Reader Consisting of Instructions for Regulating the Voice with a Rhetorical Notation... Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1840. [Gift of Willard Bicket] (Box 81)
    - A Sermon Delivered September 22, 1818 at the Dedication of the New Edifice Erected for the use of the Theological Seminary in Andover. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1818. (Box 81)
    - Lecture on the Cultivation of Spiritual Habits and Progress in Study. Andover: Flagg, Gould, and Newman, 1833. (Box 81)
    - Lectures on Homiletics and Preaching and on Public Prayer, together with sermons and letters. Andover: Flagg, Gould, and Newman, 1834. (Box 81)
  - Rhees, Rush
    - The Life of Jesus of Nazareth. New York: Scribner's Sons, 1900. (Box 82)
    - Saul's Experience as a Factor in His Theology. (American Institute of Sacred Literature, Biblical Literature essays, New Testament series, no. 6) Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1896. (Box 82)
    - The Life of Paul: Notes of Lectures to the Junior Class in Newton Theological Institution. Newton Centre, MA, 1897. (Box 82)
  - Ripley, Henry Jones
    - Fuller, J. G. Conversations Between Two Laymen, on Strict and Mixed Communion. With Dr. Griffin's letter on communion and the review of it by H.J.R. Boston: Lincoln and Edmands, 1831. (Box 83)
    - Campbell, George. Lectures on Systematic Theology and Pulpit Eloquence. Edited by HJR. Boston: Lincoln & Edmands, 1832. (Box 83)
    - The Four Gospels. Vol. I. Boston: Gould, Kendall, and Lincoln, 1837. (Box 83)
    - The Four Gospels. Vol. II. Boston: Gould, Kendall, and Lincoln, 1838. (Box 83)
    - Act of the Apostles, with Notes. Boston: Gould, Kendall, and Lincoln, 1843. (Box 83)
    - Mason, Francis. The Karen Apostle: or Memoir of Ko Thah-Byu. 1st American edition, revised by H.J.R. Boston: Gould, Kendall and Lincoln, 1843. (Box 83)
    - Sacred Rhetoric; or, Composition and Delivery of Sermons. Boston: Gould, Kendall and Lincoln, 1843. (Box 83)
    - The Church Member's Manual. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1854. (Box 84)
    - Exclusiveness of the Baptists: A Review of the Rev. Albert Barnes' Pamphlet on "Exclusivism". Boston: Gould & Lincoln, 1857. (Box 84)
    - The Epistle of the Apostle Paul to the Romans. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1860. (Box 84)
    - The Four Gospels. Vol. I. 2nd Edition. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1864. (Box 84)
    - Church Polity. Boston: Grave and Young, 1867 (Box 84)
    - The Epistle to the Hebrews. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1868. (Box 84)
  - Robinson, William C., Jr.
    - "The exegesis on the soul." NOVUM TESTAMENTUM 12 (April 1970): 102–117. (Box 65)
    - "The quest for Wrede's secret messiah." INTERPRETATION 27 (January 1973): 10–30. (Box 65)
  - Rowe, Henry Kalloch
    - HKR, ed. A Selected Bibliography on the Country Church Problem., 1909 (Box 86)
    - The Reconciliation of the Social and Evangelical in Religion. Address before the Conference of Baptist Ministers in Massachusetts, Fall River, October 24, 1911. (Box 86)
    - "Some Statistics of Church Attendance and Church Work in Rural New England." In Papers Read At The New England Country Church Association Conference On The Problems Of The Rural Church, March 13, 1911. Cambridge: Cosmos Press, 1911, 7-10 (Box 86)
    - Society; Its Origin And Development. Boston: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1916. (Box 86)
    - Modern Pathfinders Of Christianity: The Lives And Deeds Of Seven Centuries Of Christian Leaders. New York: Fleming H. Revell, 1928. (Box 86)
  - Rutenber, Culbert G.
    - The Dagger and the Cross: An Examination of Christian Pacifism (New York: Fellowship Publications, 1950). (Box 87)
    - The Reconciling Gospel (Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1960). (Box 87)
    - Prayer and Politics delivered in Philadelphia at the Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board of the American Baptist Convention, May 23, 1962. (Box 87)
    - Reconciling Agents of a Reconciling Lord (Oakland, CA: Color Art Press). …delivered at the American Baptist Convention … May 21, 1965. (Box 87)
  - Scammon, John H.
    - "Christ in Historical Novels" International Journal of Religious Education 16/6 (February 1940): 16-17. (Box 88)
    - "The Freer Manuscript." Adult Class. 38/1 (January-March 1941): 12-18. (Box 88)
    - "Studies in the Fourth Gospel." Anglican Theological Review 23/2. (April 1941): 103-117. (Box 88)
    - "Thirty Religious Books Every Layman Should Know" Bulletin of the General Theological Library. Vol. XXXVII no. 2 (January 1945). (Box 88)
    - "Our experiment with Theological Bibliographies" American Theological Librarians Association, Summary of Proceedings. (1947): 39-42. (Box 88)
    - "Trends in Old Testament Introductions from 1930 to the Present" Anglican Theological Review. 30/3 (July 1948): 150-155. (Box 88)
    - "General Evangeline Booth of the Salvation Army, by P.W. Wilson. New York, Scribner, 1948, pp. 264, $3.50" Crozer Quarterly. 26/1 (January 1949): 88-89. (Box 88)
    - "Religious Periodicals: An Annotated List." Bulletin of the General Theological Library. Vol. XLIV No. 4 (July 1952). (Box 88)
    - "Jesus Lived What He Taught" Children's Religion. 17/7 (July 1956): 16-17. (Box 88)
    - "Saying Amen" The Watchman Examiner. 53/8 (April 22, 1965): 233-234. (Box 88)
    - Living with the Psalms. (Valley Forge: The Judson Press, 1960)., 1967 (Box 88)
    - "Another Look at Psalm 104" T he Journal of Hebraic Studies. 1/1 (1969): 1-12. (Box 88)
    - "Living Peaceably With Others" Adult Class. 65/1 (September-November 1970): 10-13. (Box 88)
    - "A Personal Letter to You" in Adult Class. 69/1 (September October November 1974): (5-6). (Box 88)
    - "If I Could Find God" Baptist Leader 36/12 (March 1975): 60-64. (Box 88)
    - If I Could Find God. (Valley Forge: The Judson Press, second ed. 1978). (Box 88)
    - The Book of Proverbs: Good Advice for Good Living. (Valley Forge: The Judson Press, 1979). (Box 88)
  - Sears, Barnas
    - Classic Studies: Essays on Ancient Literature and Art. Boston: Gould, Kendall, and Lincoln, 1843. (Box 89)
    - The Life of Luther: With Special Reference to Its Earlier Periods and the Opening Scenes of the Reformation. Philadelphia: American Sunday-School Union, 1849. (Box 89)
    - Roget, Peter Mark. The Thesaurus of English Words and Phrases. Revised and Edited by B.S. Boston: Gould and Lincoln, 1874. (Box 89)
  - Shedd, William G.T.
    - A History of Christian Doctrine. (New York: Charles Scribner, vol.1 1863). (Box 90)
    - A History of Christian Doctrine. (New York: Charles Scribner, vol.2 1863). (Box 90)
  - Smith, Abraham
    - "A Second Step in African Biblical Interpretation: A Generic Reading Analysis of Acts 8:26-40." Reading from the Place, ed. Fernando Segovia and Mary Ann Tolbert. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 1995. (Box 65)
    - "Introduction: The Slavery of the New Testament." Semeia. (1-15.)., no date (Box 65)
    - Curriculum Vitae of Abraham Smith., no date (Box 65)
  - Smyth, Egbert Coffin
    - ECS, et al. Progressive Orthodoxy. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin, 1892. (Box 91)
    - ECS, et al. The Divinity of Jesus Christ: An Exposition of the Origin and Reasonableness of the Belief of the Christian Church. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin, 1894. (Box 91)
    - ECS and George Harris. Order for Evening Worship. Andover, 1899. (Box 91)
  - Stackhouse, Max Lynn
    - The Righteousness of the Kingdom. Edited with introduction by Max L. Stackhouse., 1968 (Box 92)
    - The Death Of Dialogue And Beyond. Edited with introduction by Sandford Seltzer and Max L. Stackhouse. New York: Friendship Press, 1969. (Box 92)
    - Reparations: A Call To Repentance?. (Paper prepared as two lectures for the Pre-Synod Conference on The Local Church in God's Mission and Crisis in the Nation, sponsored by the United Church Board of Homeland Ministries), 1969 (Box 92)
    - The Ethics Of Necropolis: An Essay On The Military Industrial Complex And The Quest For A Just Peace. Boston: Beacon Press, 1971. (Box 92)
    - Gird Up Your Minds. (Chapel Sermon, March 17, 1971.) (Box 92)
    - Toward A Theology Of Institutional Change. Transcript of a talk to the American Home Mission Board, June, 1971. (Box 92)
    - Ethics and the Urban Ethos: An Essay in Social Theory and Theological Reconstruction. Boston: Beacon Press, 1972. (Box 93)
    - "Religion, technology and urbanity." In The Citizen And The City: Communications For A Humane Urban Community: A Conference Of Fifty Persons, 1-11. St. Louis: Institute For Theological Encounter With Science And Technology, April 19, 1974. (Box 93)
    - In Order To Establish Justice: A Report On Justice And The U.S. Military. (Report submitted to the 10th. General Synod, Minneapolis, MN, July 27-July 1, 1975.; UCC Task Force on Ministries to Military Personnel). (Box 93)
    - Testimony to the Senate Ethics Committee. April 13, 1977. (Box 93)
    - The Worldly Holiness of Learning. June 29, 1980. (Box 93)
    - The Church and Political Life: Back to Basics?. (Address to the Mass. Council of Churches, January, 1981.) (Box 93)
    - "Developing a responsible public theology." (Transcript of an address delivered at The Ecumenical Event, National Council of Churches, November 5-7, 1981.) (Box 93)
    - "A Puritan's pilgrimage: beyond the iron cage." Union Seminary Quarterly. 37 (1982): 205-216. (Box 93)
    - "The world religions and political democracy: some comparative reflections." Religion and Society. 29 (December 1982): 19-49. Typed manuscript. (Box 93)
    - "An ecumenical perspective on neo-evangelical politics." Journal of Law and Religion. 1 (Summer 1983): 203-214. (Box 93)
    - Creeds, Society And Human Rights. Grand Rapids: William B. Eerdmans, 1984. (Box 93)
    - "Jesus and economics: a century of reflection." In The Bible in American Law, Politics and Political Rhetoric, ed. James Turner Johnson, 107-151. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1985. (Typed manuscript.) (Box 94)
    - "Mission of the Church: A Cross-Cultural Perspective." Twist, A Forum on Third World Concerns. Volume IV, Numbers 1 & 2 (July, 1986): 21-24. (Box 94)
    - The Church As A Paradigm For Voluntary Associations. Speech given at James Luther Adams' 85th birthday celebration. [no publishing information], 1986 (Box 94)
    - Public Theology and Political Economy: Christian Stewardship in Modern Society. Grand Rapids: William B. Eerdman's, 1987. (Box 94)
    - Apologia: Contextualization, Globalization And Mission In Theological Education. Grand Rapids: William B. Eerdmans, 1988. (Box 94)
    - "Divisions and Consensus: An `Ecumenical' Response." Stewardship Journal 2/3 and 4 (Summer-Fall 1992): 56-60. (Box 94)